

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Trina Dutta Trina Dutta (1) Featured | 7 Expertise in technical procedural documentation in accordance with ISO and CMMI regulatory procedures. Experienced in different roles such as Training Specialist, Senior Consultant, Software Testing Engineer and Business Analyst. Current Designation: Business Analyst, Senior Associate Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: 3I Infotech Itd Notice Period: 2 Months Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: MCA[Computers] Pref. Location: Noida, Delhi / NCR Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Business Analyst Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married Key Skills: application development, business analysis, requirement analysis and elicitation, quality assurance,resource allocation and monitoring, client management, proposal writing, srs fsd , prototype, manual, sdlc life cycle,uat testing ,ms visio,Training Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21

Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects | Work Authorization

### Summary

 $Oracle\ certified\ SQL\ expert\ and\ Java\ professional\ with\ 7\ years\ of\ experience\ of\ supporting\ Business\ solution,\ Application$ Requirement gathering and analysis to create prototypes, documentation and conducting training. Holds Master of Computer Application and have experience in all key components of the project Life cycle along with Testing in UAT. Handled sessions and presentations on technical and non-technical subjects for corporates and students. Experienced with different roles as Training Specialist, Senior Consultant, Software Testing Engineer and Business Analyst.

## **Work Experience**

3I Infotech Itd as Business Analyst, Senior Associate

Aug 2016 to Till Date

Organization: 3i-Infotech Ltd., Location: Noida, Patna(Onsite), Designation: Senior Associate

Job profile: Business Analyst

Experience: 2.5 years (From 1st March 2017 till date)

Organization: 3i-Infotech Ltd, Location: Noida/Patna, Designation: Consultant

Experience: 7 months (From 12th August 2016-1st March)

Current Designation : Business Analyst

Location: Noida Key activities:

- \* Meeting with the clients and the consultants for Requirement Specification
- \* Preparing Project proposal, Queries, Scope, Functional Architecture based on RFP
- \* Coordinating with Technical and Developer team for functional module specifications
- \* Responsible for Feasibility study of the project
- \* Responsible for Preparing and documenting the Functional Part
- \* Responsible for preparing Prototypes, Functional Requirement study and System Requirement Specification

NIIT Itd as Consultant Aug 2010 to Sep 2015

Organization: NIIT Ltd, Location: Gaya, Designation: Consultant Experience: Experience: 1.5Year(From Feb 2014 to Sept 2015)

Organization: NIIT Ltd., Location: Chennai, Designation: Training Consultant

Experience: 3 Years (From 4th August 2010 to August 2013)

**Designation: Training Consultant** 

Location: Chennai

- Key Responsibilities:
- \* Responsible to handle trainings for trainees, corporates and Engineering students
- \* Held multiple roles as a Regional Domain Expert in DB, Cloud Evangelist
- \* Handled technical sessions on Java, Net-C#, ADO, Asp, Oracle DB, Automation Testing on IBM Tool
- \* Worked on Project: 'Secure Processing System on Online Transaction' for Brikcham Institute, Burkit Road, Chennai

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Feb 2009 to Aug 2010

Software Development in Java.

^ Back to Top

#### Education

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Ranchi University in 2000

PG: MCA (Computers), Correspondence/Distance Learning from Indira Gandhi National Open University (IGNOU) in 2009

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: **PGDCA** 

^ Back to Top

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java, JDBC,EJB, C#, C++, GUI, UML,OOAD			
Oracle10g, Testing, PL/SQL			
Microsoft Excel			
MS-Project			
SQL, MYSQL			
ASP.NET			
ADO.NET			

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
bengali	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

## **Projects**

Project Title: NHA Portal Client: National Health Authority Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: National Health Authority (NHA) is the apex body responsible for implementing Indias flagship public health insurance scheme AB-PMJAY. The proposed system is a IT solution which maintains the details and records of Beneficiaries of scheme PMJAY and track all the records of claim transaction of PMJAY beneficiaries. The portal is envisaged to be used by NHA and its stakeholders to view the data in an analyzable capability.

Project Title: SDUY, Rajasthan Client: RISL, Govt of Rajasthan Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Sadak Durghatna Upchar Yojna (SDUY), is the scheme to provide immediate help and medical assistance to the Road Traffic Injuries (RTIs) victims which has been initiated by Government of Rajasthan through Department of Medical, Health and Family Welfare, Rajasthan (DHFW). Through this project, Govt. of Rajasthan is looking for implementing a state of the art ICT platform for SDUY and BSKY schemes as an extension to existing BSBY application. Govt. wishes to use the existing application to the maximum possible extent. The project covers features like Patient case registration, Package booking/ Treatment details, Patient admission and discharge Claim submission, Payment mechanism, Reconciliation and liability management with taxation, Death Claim Submission/Approval, Hospital empanelment etc. Patients under SDUY can be transferred to BSBY after 48 hours for further treatment and in case of death, record can be transferred to BSKY from SDUY based on eligibility of the beneficiary.

Project Title: Implementation of Integrated Core Solution - (PNBHFL) Client: PNB Housing Finance Limited (PNB HFL). PNBHFL, New Delhi

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: PNBHFL intends to drive up business volumes for both its lending & deposit portfolios. PNBHFL required an Integrated Core Solution for its functioning. The project aims ERP Implementation for automating all the internal processes of PNBHFL covering below:

Lead Management System (LMS) Loan Organization System Loan Management System

Collections Deposits

Human Resource Management System

Document Management System

Integrated Accounting Customer Service Applications Cacamor Cornoc, pprocasorio

Project Title: BSBY, Rajasthan Client: RISL, Govt of Rajasthan Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2017 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Bhamashah Swasthya BimaYojana, an initiative of the Government of the state of Rajasthan, empowers citizens to avail of Cashless Medical Treatment. The benefits of this Scheme are available to families registered under National Food Security Act (NFSA) and Rashtriya Swasthya Bima Yojana (RSBY), primarily to those incapable of paying medical treatment expenses due to unstable financial conditions.

The principal aim of the Scheme was to provide financial security against illness. To achieve this objective the Application had to operate transparently and in real time.

The success of the Application hinged on

- 1. A well-integrated workflow and intuitive processes
- 2. Easy to use service points
- 3. Identity checks to ensure the benefits accrue to the intended beneficiary
- 4. Integrity checks to guard against fund leakages

The Solution provides both Private and Government hospitals a role based login to the BSBY application. Service delivery points named as BSBY Kiosk, known as Swasthya Marqda

Project Title: MNSSBY

Client: Department of Planning and Development. Govt. of Bihar

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2016 - Till Date
Project Location: Patna Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Role: Other Team Size: 20

Skill Used: Technical Expertise, Software Skills - Java, JDBC,EJB,Oracle10g, C#, C++, GUI, UML,OOAD,SQL Oracle10g, Testing, PL/SQL, Analytical - MS-Project, Database- Oracle, MySql, UML - Microsoft Visio, Prototype/Wireframe - Microsoft Dreamweaver

Role Description: \*Meeting with the clients and consultants for Requirement Specification

\*Responsible for Feasibility study for the project

\*Responsible for Preparing and documenting the Functional Part

\*Coordinating with Technical team for functional specification.

Project Details: The project Integrated IT Solution for Mukhyamantri Nischay Swayam Sahayata Bhatta Yojana (MNSSBY), Bihar Student Credit Card (BSCC) scheme and Kushal Yuva Programme(KYP) has been launched by the Government of Bihar.

The proposed system addresses the Enterprise Portal, Registration Module, Verification Module, Payment Module, Report Management, Database Management, Reporting engine, Integration with external system, Call centre Management, Interactive Voice Response System (IVRS), Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Hardware and network support and maintenance.

The external systems to be integrated with the Mukhyamantri Nischay Swayam Sahayata Bhatta Yojana (MNSSBY) application are following:

State Examination Board/Universities

Department of Labor

Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI)

State Level Bank Data

External Hardware (Scanner, camera and Biometric Device) as provided by the client

^ Back to Top

### **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General Countries: India
Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.